Av. Alanis Maria Laurindo de Oliveira, 390.

Fortaleza, Ceará.

☑ joelxr@gmail.com
③ joelxr.github.io
in joelxr

⋓ joelxr

? joelxr

# Joel Xavier Rocha

5+ years of software development and analysis, today I work at CPQi as technical leader where we build, implement and support financial market systems for the leading American economies, working with the proper technology for this, such as Calypso and Findur.

#### Education

2008–2015 **Degree**, Federal Institute of Education, Science and Tech-

nology - CE, Fortaleza.

Computer Engineer

2014–2018 Certification, ANBIMA.

CPA-20

## Languages

Portuguese Native

English Advanced

Spanish Intermediary

#### Skills

- o Programing language and technologies:
  - Java: JEE, JSP, EL, EJB, JSF, JUnit, Hibernate, JPA, Mockito, Powermock, Selenium, Android, Spring, JasperReports, VRaptor.
  - C#: .NET Framework 3.5.
  - Javascript: JQuery, Dojo, YUI, DWR, ExtJS, Ember, AngularJS.
  - Others: Ruby On Rails, Python, Delphi, C, LATEX
- Development tools:
  - Application servers: IBM Websphere, Glassfish, Tomcat, JBoss, Wildfly, IIS.
  - Database: Oracle, SQL Server.
  - Versions system: Git, SVN e CVS.

- Others: Maven, Gradle, Sonar, Jenkins, Travis, PMD.
- o Infrastructure:
  - Linux, Shell script.

### **Experience**

2012-Today CPQi, Technical Leader and Technical Analyst.

At CPQi, I have contributed to five solutions developed to improve the Brazil and Chile financial markets. All these solutions were developed to banks and agencies which are strongly engaged in daily trades. Our clients have trusted their most important and valuable systems to us, to develop and support it.

2010-2012 Ebix, Senior Developer.

I worked at the maintenance and development for the WEB systems of the leading insurance companies in Brazil. Mostly of these insurance systems were running in production or in pre production environment. To delivery correctly all the clients requirements, we made a strongly partnership with all the insurances team.

2009-2010 **Usix**, *Trainee*.

I worked at the maintenance and development of WEB solutions. Initially, 20h per week then 30h per week. Working with Java and MVC and Command design patterns, some features we written in Java Script.

2008-2009 Artificial Intelligence Lab. Lambda, Volunteer.

Developed a global monitoring system written in Ruby On Rails and Google Maps API. In this lab we had a lot of study cells, such as Java and Ruby.